<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>N &amp; R</title>
    <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on N &amp; R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.numbersandreality.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: Installing Rust Lang on Alpine (With just LLVM Dependencies)</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/notes/alpine-wsl/rust-lang-on-alpine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/notes/alpine-wsl/rust-lang-on-alpine/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s install Rust Programming Language on Alpine Linux, with almost no GNU Dependencies. We will use the offical Rust Lang installer (rustup) and we will use LLVM toolchain when we need C toolchain for things like linking, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Installing Go Lang on Alpine (Without GCC or LLVM Dependencies)</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/notes/alpine-wsl/go-lang-on-alpine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/notes/alpine-wsl/go-lang-on-alpine/</guid>
      <description>Download and install latest version of Go Programming Language on Alpine Linux without any dependencies. Just vanilla Go Lang from the offical website. No extra libraries, nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: LLVM/Clang on Alpine</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/notes/alpine-wsl/clang-on-alpine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/notes/alpine-wsl/clang-on-alpine/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s setup a relatively GNU Free C Programming setup on Alpine Linux. We will use LLVM toolchain for almost everything expect for libgcc and libstdc++</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 0: Installing Alpine on WSL 2</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/notes/alpine-wsl/alpine-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/notes/alpine-wsl/alpine-wsl/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to setup the latest version of Alpine Linux on WSL 2 without using Microsoft Store. We will just use the latest vanilla rootfs from offical Alpine Linux Page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/about/</guid>
      <description>This corner of the web is a place to sit back, relax and enjoy all things related to Science, Computing and Mathematics. The InterWebs can be an overwhelming place with daily occurances of hype-trains, counter-hype arguments, crises and uproars.
If all of that stresses you out, professionally or personally, make yourself some hot chocolate and go through some of my articles. Take things slow, one byte at a time.
If you are in a fix, feel free to reach out to ranvir@numbersandreality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Multiple GitHub Accounts from a Single Shell</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/multiple-github-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/multiple-github-accounts/</guid>
      <description>I have two GitHub accounts; One for work and one for personal projects. In this post, I describe my thought process when I was trying to easily switch between the two on my local computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WSL setup for Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/wsl-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/wsl-setup/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s learn how we can automate a WSL/WSL2 environment to be setup exactly the way we want it to be. This way if you break your WSL2 installation you can easily reproduce the exact setup within minutes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web APIs and integrations</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/webapis-and-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/webapis-and-integration/</guid>
      <description>I always keep running into issues with various web services and how they integrate with one another. There is always some edge cases that they have missed, or something that I have been stupid about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to the Basics</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/back-to-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/back-to-basics/</guid>
      <description>Rambling about the state of software. The lack of organization and discipline that the industry shows at large. Even I am guilty of these crimes, but I wanted to take a step back and think about the overall landscape at large.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting Science back in Computer Science</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/science-in-cs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/science-in-cs/</guid>
      <description>Its time we drop the titles of developers, coders, programmers, etc. Because building complex, mission-critical, computing infrastructure involves much more than that. It is needs to be more rigourous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Servers and Whatnot</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/servers-and-whatnot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/servers-and-whatnot/</guid>
      <description>A note for my future-self when he feels a bit lost in the weeds. To think clearly, to read and write clearly, and when time comes&amp;hellip;to act out the truth!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Cloud Checklist</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/cloud-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/cloud-checklist/</guid>
      <description>Important aspects of cloud computing that every provider should work hard on maintaining and every organization should expect from their vendors. It is not so much about the technology but about the underlying guiding principles and mindset that engineers should have while building a product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you may not want to go &#34;Full-Cloud&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/full-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.numbersandreality.com/posts/full-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Thinking about going &amp;ldquo;Full Cloud!&amp;rdquo;? Think again! Organizations and individuals alike need to think for themselves instead of scrambling to learn and use whatever new shiny technology gets talked about the most. Maybe it is time we take engineer for the discipline that it is&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
